# Visahl Samson David Selvam

visahlsamson@gmail.com 💠 +65 9040 2769 💠

### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Proactive manager, team builder and tactical planner with ability to attract and secure solid working relationships at the strategic level and translate business needs into technical specifications. Expertised in Cyber Security with two years of experience as information security analyst, with an undergraduate degree in Cyber Security equipped with AI-Cyber security project background.

### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Soft skills: Innovative, Self-learning, Adaptable, Team player, Problem-solving, Research and Communication.
- Technical skills: Vulnerability assessment and penetration testing, Computer forensics, Python, Shell Script,
  Network and system hardening, Risk assessments. AWS, Project management.
- Interests: Threat intelligence, Machine Learning, Psychology, Entrepreneurship, Wireframing, UI/UX, Application development.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### NODESPAY TEKH PTE LTD

June 2022 - Present

# **Chief Technology Officer**

MacPherson, Singapore

- Oversee software, hardware, and server infrastructure to suit the growth of the development
- Guide and review the overall technical vision with the adoption model.
- Shaping core and non-core technical software/hardware applications that integrate for approved third-party or partners with an application programming interface.
- Align and apply risk analysis to meet future planning such as Blockchain, Artificial Intelligence and Financial System.
- Define, and architect application flow, and ensure the application meets the regulatory requirements (from MAS) also globally recognised framework ISO27001.

# **Highlights**

• Implemented "ISO27001-2022 controls" framework throughout the organisation with special focus on Secure Software Development Process.

## **EAGLE I SECURITY SERVICES**

June 2021 - May 2022

# IT Manager

Ubi, Singapore

- Facilitate project scope definition and project plan development (inclusive of scope, design, schedule, resource plan, issues & process).
- Manage communication, which includes dissemination of related project documentation and distributing status reports, meeting notes.
- Review and development of security framework, information security policies, processes/procedures, and guidelines on an ongoing basis.
- Conduct vulnerability assessment and penetration tests, perform network hardening.
- Provide Ad Hoc IT support, and media creation for digital marketing activities.
- Develop applications to support part of the security products such as Visitor Management System, IoT controllers based on DevSecOps framework.

## **Highlights**

- Implemented "Data Protection by Design" framework from PDPC to all the new and existing web and mobile applications.
- Configured the office IT infrastructure based on **PDPC Recommended practises**.

## **ALTIUS EQUIPMENTS**

# May 2017 – May 2019 Y ANALYST Bangalore, India

### INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST

- Installing, administering, and troubleshooting network security solutions.
- Performing vulnerability and penetration tests, identifying and defending against threats, and developing disaster recovery plans.
- Configuring security systems, analysing security requirements, and recommending improvements.
- Creating network policies and authorization roles and defending against unauthorised access, modifications, and destruction.
- Training staff to understand and use security protocols.

**Highlights:** First person to implement an IDS solution to provide more effective security.

# RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCE

# Agency for Science, Technology and Research (A\* Star)

May 2020- Dec 2020

Project title: ML-powered web application for Phishing Detection

Singapore

- Worked under the supervision of A\*Star, and their researchers from the Institute of High-Performance Computing. The project involved the usage of Machine learning (especially Natural Language Processing) to address one of the well-known cyber-attack vectors which is Phishing.
- Using this web application, people can check whether the URL is a Phishing or a legitimate URL. Applications used: Flask (Python-based web framework), Anaconda framework, Python 3.

## **INDUSTRY CERTIFICATIONS**

- EC-Council Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH Practical) December 2020
- ELearnSecurity eJPT (Junior Penetration Tester) January 2022

### **EDUCATION**

Edith Cowan University, Australia (Offshore campus at PSB Academy, Singapore)

May 2019 - Dec 2020

Bachelor of Science in Cyber Security

Cornerstone International College

Jul 2015 – May 2017

Pearson Level 5 HND in Computing and Systems Development

Chennai, India

Singapore

## PROJECT PORTFOLIO AND OTHER REFERENCES

• LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/v-samson/

• GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Samson-DVS">https://github.com/Samson-DVS</a>

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• DOB: 30 July 1998

• Proficient Languages: Tamil, English, Telugu

#### REFERENCES

Available on request